Damned be the ties that bind
The Atoning is a drama, horror, thriller film directed by Michael Williams.
Vera, Ray, and Sam, a seemingly normal family, are
haunted by more than mere ghosts.
The lingering horror of their past threatens their ability to function as a
loving family until they become enlightened by a mystical encounter.
From that moment on, they're thrust into a horror worse
than anything they've ever experienced.
Personal demons manifest and tear the family apart from the
inside out as they come to terms with their past.
Sam, played by Cannon Bosarge.
Ray, played by Michael LaCour.
Vera, played by Virginia Newcomb.
Charon Lilith, played by Dorothy Weems.
Sarah, played by Sherri Eakin.
Julie, played by Ashlyn Jade Lopez.
Atonement is a 2007 romantic war tragedy film directed by Joe Wright and starring James
McAvoy, Keira Knightley, Saoirse Ronan, Romola Garai, and Vanessa Redgrave.
It is based on the 2001 novel by Ian McEwan.
The film chronicles a crime and its consequences over
six decades, beginning in the 1930s.
It was produced for StudioCanal and filmed in England.
Distributed in most of the world by Universal Studios, it was released theatrically in the United Kingdom
on 7 September 2007 and in North America exactly three months later on 7 December 2007.
Atonement opened both the 2007 Vancouver International Film
Festival and the 64th Venice International Film Festival.
Wright, at age 35, was the youngest director ever to open the Venice event.
The film was a commercial success and earned a worldwide gross of
approximately $129 million against a budget of $30 million.
Critics praised its acting, emotional depth, Wright's direction, Dario Marianelli's score, the
cinematography, editing, visuals, and the film's incorporation of historic events.
Among numerous accolades, Atonement was nominated in seven categories at the 80th Academy Awards, including Best
Picture, Best Supporting Actress (for Ronan), Best Adapted Screenplay, and Best Original Score, which it won.
It also garnered fourteen nominations at the 61st British Academy Film Awards, winning both Best Film
and Production Design; and won the Golden Globe Award for Best Motion Picture – Drama.
The film explores themes of infidelity, afterlife, supernatural, puzzle, murder.
The tone is dark and lighthearted and emotional.